<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>LinkedIn - Category - Dr. Anandana Kapur</title>
        <link>http://192.168.0.247:35729/categories/linkedin/</link>
        <description>LinkedIn - Category - Dr. Anandana Kapur</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>contact.anandana@gmail.com (Dr. Anandana Kapur)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>contact.anandana@gmail.com (Dr. Anandana Kapur)</webMaster><copyright>Dr. Anandana Kapur</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 01:00:00 &#43;0540</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://192.168.0.247:35729/categories/linkedin/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>The Role Of Technology In Empowering The Crafts Sector In India: Some Learnings</title>
    <link>http://192.168.0.247:35729/the-role-of-technology-in-empowering-the-crafts-sector-in-india-some-learnings/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 01:00:00 &#43;0540</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://192.168.0.247:35729/the-role-of-technology-in-empowering-the-crafts-sector-in-india-some-learnings/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I recently moderated a session titled &ldquo;From Low-Tech to AI: Building Tech-Led Efficiencies in Craft-Value Chains&rdquo; at the <a href="https://www.kulaconclave.com/kula-2024-highlights" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Kula Conclave 2024</a>. The discussion explored the diverse opportunities that arise from tech adoption in the craft sector, while also challenging conventional ideas of what “tech” entails.<br />
<br /></p>
<h2 id="technology-is-multi-faceted-artisan-needs-too">Technology is multi-faceted, artisan needs too</h2>
<p>Conversations with MeMeraki, The Center for Pastoralism, SASHA and Rug Republic highlighted the multifaceted nature of technology—spanning digital, environmental, materials, design, and low-tech solutions. We examined applications such as traceability, authentication, concept iteration, sustainability, and human-centered design to empower artisan entrepreneurs.<br /></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A Page from My Diary: 2024</title>
    <link>http://192.168.0.247:35729/a-page-from-my-diary-2024/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 01:00:00 &#43;0540</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://192.168.0.247:35729/a-page-from-my-diary-2024/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I arrived in the U.S. on the eve of the elections — a moment charged with anticipation and reflection on the state of democracy. Against this backdrop I had the honor of seeing five of my portraits unveiled at the <a href="https://ash.harvard.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Harvard Ash Center for Democratic Governance and Innovation</a>, celebrating leaders who have shaped and upheld democratic values.<br />
<br /></p>
<h2 id="the-opening">The opening</h2>
<p>Colleagues and friends joined me for a tour of the space, where we reflected on the opportunities and responsibilities of keeping democracy alive. Creating these pieces was a deeply reflective journey. Through stitches, textures, and up-cycled materials, I sought to honor the resilience and light of these leaders, while paying tribute to the layers of history and culture that shape our understanding of leadership.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
